Let's now discuss types of exam questions
to expect.
So most you'll see on the next slide will
be scenario situational.
Probably about 95% of the questions.
They'll give you a scenario, this,
this, this is happening on your project.
What is the next best thing you should do?
So there's usually some problem.
So you'll solve a problem.
them.
You'll investigate, evaluate, you'll talk.
All right, talk with your team.
So most of the questions will be like
that.
This next bullet, there will
be questions that have a
lot of extraneous information
in them, red herrings.
They are purposely trying to throw you
off.
Can you answer the question actually being
asked that will be so important?
Find out what is.
asking.
There will be irrelevant scenarios,
long-winded verbiage, mathematical questions.
There are very few now formulas that
you'll have to calculate.
When I took my exam in 2012, I had like 20
to 25 formulas.
I happen to like math.
Formulas are not subjective.
If you know a formula, you'll get it right
but for the exam now you'll have very few
mathematical questions you'll be given a
scenario you will have to understand what
the formula outcome is what a schedule
performance index of 1.2 means what a cost
performance index of 0.75 means all right
to be able to show the progress on your
project all right so that's what you're
going to need to understand.
There will also be questions that won't
seem to make any sense and are vague.
I better get used to it.
You'll be okay.
If I can do it, you can do it.
All right.
And they will also present real world
scenarios versus PMI.
You are now in the PMI world.
So unless you have a
PMO, project management
office, you report to that
is based on the Pembock.
Let your real world experience go.
And I mean, let it go.
You are in the PMI world.
Keep on your PMI hat as
you're going through this course,
going back to study and
take those simulated exams.
You can Google free ones.
All right.
We also have some additional ones as part
of the course.
But you want to take those situational
simulated exams.
and they will present a scenario and some
of the answers will be what a lot of us do
in the real world do not answer those in a
real world way always the PMI way so you
will learn that all right this next bullet
there might be one possible option there
can be more than one correct answer so you
will have to of the answers they give you
find out what doesn't fit belong in
whatever question scenario they're giving
you and then focus on the last two and
which is the best that you should do
problem solving evaluating investigating
those types of things you might also have
questions where you have to choose two or
three answers that's common now too you
will see drag-and-drop
where you might see a process
and you have to drag it to
the correct process group.
You might see a few of those.
Some true or false, a correct answer to a
different question.
On the PMP exam itself, one question will
have nothing to do with another question.
So, you know, in some of your study
materials, we build on things.
But on the exam, one question will have
nothing to do with another.
So read the question.
and carefully know what it's asking.
You do need to memorize
things, like some of the formulas,
at least to be familiar with
them, but your process map.
In your Pimpock on page 25 is the process
map.
You should know that like the back of your
hand.
You need to know exactly where you are and
no, I'm not doing Father's Unholy Ghost.
I do this in class too.
Where are you in a process group?
Where are you in a knowledge?
area.
That is something you need to know like
the back of your hand.
Draw it as you're studying.
And this very last one, only one of the
options might address the question.
All the other options might be incorrect.
So just read the questions and the answers
carefully.